PROPHET T.B. JOSHUA - The Synagogue Church Of All Nations
I believe God will use me to add to your joy.
Amen!
Already, there is joy in the house.
There is joy - you will agree with me that there is joy in the house.
Yes.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let's quickly take a look at the book of John 15:7.
"If you remain in Me and My Words remain in you,
ask whatever you wish, and it will be done for you."
This shows that Christ and His Word are one.
Simple. Take a look again.
"If you remain in Me and My Words remain in you,
ask whatever you wish, and it will be done for you."
This means, Christ and His Word are one.
Jesus - Word , Word - Jesus.
Christ and His Word are one.
Hallelujah!
If the Word dwells in you, it produces prayer fruit.
F-R-U-I-T
How can this Word dwell in us?
It is not only committing the Word to memory,
because of where we are coming from
and how you are brought up.
You are educated and in education, academy, you need to memorise.
But coming to the house of God - the Bible -
it is not only committing the Word to memory which is indeed valuable
- it is good to memorise -
but allowing the Word to become an integral part of you.
You know we have a sitting room, and we have a bedroom.
So when you choose to memorise the Word,
it will only be acting in the sitting room but not in the bedroom.
But you need it in the bedroom because it lives in you.
It must dominate you, rule you and sanctify your spirit nature.
The reason why the Word must be an integral part of you is
because Jesus can only dwell in your heart through faith.
And Bible faith comes from God's Word.
I mean Bible faith; not faith - there are many faiths, all kinds of faith.
Bible faith comes from God's Word.
Like it is defined in the book of Romans 10:17.
Let me put it the way it is written there.
"Faith cometh by hearing and by hearing the Word of God."
When the Word dwells in you, dominates you, rules you,
lives in you, it will produce prayer fruit.
When you say, "In Jesus' name, in Jesus' name, Amen, Give me biscuit...",
you just receive them.
"Oh Jesus, Oh Jesus, here I am!
Forgive me, forgive me!"
You receive those things - these are the prayer fruits - if the Word dominates you.
The Word dominating you becomes the Lordship of Christ in you.
The Lordship; Christ Himself.
Letting the Word have right of way in your life is letting Christ Himself have right of way.
Say to your neighbour:
Letting the Word have right of way in your life is letting Christ have right of way.
Letting the Word have right of way in your life is letting Christ Himself have right of way.
If the Word has no right of way in your life, forget it.
So this is Christ - you go straight; it's like a magnet.
Nail - magnet.
If the magnet is there and the nail is here,
there's no way they can jump and attract - connect.
The Word dominating you is the Lordship of Christ Himself.
Message Title: BE AN IMITATOR OF GOD
The Lord will not meet you because you imitate what someone else did.
The Lord will only meet you when you obey what He told you to do, by His Spirit, based on His Word.
That is, act in obedience to God.
Like someone shared a testimony just now and said, "Praise the Lord!
The Morning Water, I sprayed it three times this way, four times this way.
At 12 midnight I sprayed it."
You quickly write down all those statements.
By the time you get your Morning Water, you get home and spray it.
"How many times did the lady say she sprayed it?
Oh! Four times!
This time - twelve midnight - four times!"
You now set your clock to 12 midnight.
When it rings, "Oh! I want to spray my Morning Water".
It will not work because this is imitation.
Lord I want to be like Jesus
Inner my heart
That is it.
Everything that becomes of us today is purely imitation.
You went to school because someone studied marketing and later became a general manager.
You say to your parents, "I want to study marketing".
"I want to study marketing." - "Why?"
"Because that man is a millionaire and he studied marketing."
That is the only reason why you want to study marketing.
You have abandoned God's vision in your life.
You see a soldier or a military man with uniform - a general.
Beautiful!
You say, "Oh! I want to be a soldier!"
Just because of that very attractive uniform, you abandon God's calling in your life.
That's imitation of man.
Some people that are looking on might have seen some beautiful attire.
By the time they leave from here,
they will now begin to look for that attire in the market;
you want to buy the same uniform.
And I know many of you might have gone to the car park to see some beautiful cars.
You see a posh car - "Let me take a picture."
"When I leave church today, I have to look for this type of car. I need it."
Our life is full of imitation.
You look at different styles of hair, the way people plait their hair.
Message Title: BE AN IMITATOR OF GOD
Life is full of imitation.
This is why we are very limited in our thinking, doings and way.
You can't go beyond when you are a type that copies.
You base your life on copying.
There is so much weakness in copying.
You can imagine how many business cards you have in your pocket.
You are the architect, you are the lawyer,
you are the accountant, and you are this
because you don't know what to do again - your copy.
Each time you see someone who is prosperous in his career,
you abandon your career - you jump into that career.
Prosperity is not evidence that you are called.
You can be rich in doing what you are doing
and yet you are not called for that job from Heaven.
You can be very rich in what you are doing
and yet, it's not your calling from Heaven.
The end will prove that it is your calling.
Tell your neighbour.
The end will prove that what I'm doing is my calling from God.
Tell your neighbour. Don't be afraid.
The end will prove that what you are doing is your calling from God.
If there is nothing like that - people like me, where would I be today?
This is inheritance from Apostles.
The price they paid is what I am enjoying today.
So the price you are paying today, children yet unborn also need to enjoy them.
This is why we are saying that the world is coming to an end because everyone is copying.
No one is patient enough to wait for God, to hear from God.
You copy little things.
Even in the world today, we encourage copying.
When your children want to sit for an exam,
they are given opportunity for first choice and second choice.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So alternative everywhere.
Where are we going?
So it will be too soon for you now to say this is my calling.
What I'm doing is what I'm called from Heaven to do.
No! The beginner is not the owner but the finisher.
Tell you neighbour: The beginner is not the owner of the job but the finisher.
When you start, you begin to run faster faster faster
and someone has been struggling to get to you.
But before getting to the end where you can receive the award, you suddenly fall down.
The one that is coming with effort passes you, and he will be the one to receive the award.
Issue of faith is an issue we should critically look into and see how it really affects your life.
Are you living by faith? Are you a faith man?
If you continue to copy and you are not patient enough to listen to God for direction,
you will go well and still come back where you started.
This is why you see people are up and down.
There is so much epileptic system of life today.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
A copy cannot stand the test of time.
This is why when challenges come, you lament and complain.
Challenges will come but a copy man cannot stand the challenges.
Who is the master of copy? Man is the master of copy.
But the master of original is God - God is the master.
No one can be built up with philosophy or theory about the Word.
You cannot be built up to walk with Jesus; it's not possible.
Or on the history - it is the history in the Bible that you rely on.
You want to hear story about Elijah and others. No!
The Word must live in you, and you must live in the Word to walk with Jesus.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
As the deer panteth for the water
So my soul longeth after Thee
You alone are my heart's desire
And I long to worship Thee
You alone are my strength and shield
To You alone may my spirit yield
You alone are my heart's desire
And I long to worship Thee
Hallelujah
You're my Friend
And You are my Brother
Even though You are a King
Sing on - I love you...
I love You more than any other
So much more than anything
You alone are my strength and shield
To You alone may my spirit yield
You alone are my heart's desire
And I long to worship Thee
Hallelujah!
You may be seated. Thank you.
We can only be a part of Christ when the Word dominates us.
You become part of Christ; then you can bring Christ on the scene.
"Jesus!" - you see Him on the scene.
Instantly!
You can only make a very thorough decision, true decision
when you begin to see each day as if it were your last day on earth.
But just look at yourself - "today's my last day on earth" -
you know you are going to meet Him,
so just take a decision. Let it be in your heart any time.
You say, "I want to accept Jesus, I want to follow Him.
Today is my last day on earth, I want to follow Him".
Just take that decision with the word "today is my last day on earth".
If today is your last day on earth, what else again.
You are finished with the world.
Over there. And He is the head of the immaterial world.
He is the head.
Invisible world - He is the head.
And you leave the visible world to the invisible world.
You will meet Him there.
Just take that decision today: "Today is my last day on earth."
You will stop all what you do; you accept Him.
Take that decision with this word of encouragement.
Your heart needs to be free; you need a free heart, free spirit to accept Jesus.
You are not free.
Free spirit can only attract Jesus - free spirit.
Your spirit is not free. So many things are going on in your heart.
A free spirit attracts the Spirit of God.
Free spirit.
To accept Jesus as our Lord and Saviour, begin to meditate on what you hear now.
The message you are receiving, begin to meditate on it, not think.
I'm not saying begin to think about the message.
No! Don't think about the message.
You can only think about your situation but meditate on the Word you hear now.
Turn it over and over again in your heart.
If you don't turn it over and over, it will remain on your lips.
There is a difference between the Word on your lips and the Word in your heart.
It is the Word in your heart that would release the authority.
There is power in your mouth; the belief in your heart is released by faith out of your mouth.
Let someone say, "There is power in my mouth;
the belief in my heart is released by faith out of my mouth.
Again.
There is power in my mouth; the belief in my heart is released by faith out of my mouth.
There's power in my mouth
When you say, "In Jesus' name! Amen!", power comes.
But before that power can be in your mouth, the belief in your heart must be released by faith.
If the belief is released by faith, it comes from your mouth again.
There's power in my mouth; the belief in my heart is released by faith out of my mouth.
So this means faith is believing with my heart and confessing with my mouth.
So any moment from now we will begin to see what we are talking about - the power.
"Be healed!" - You see shaking.
"I'm healed, I am healed!" - How does this come about?
Power in the mouth comes when faith release the belief in our heart.
"I believe" - No!
Faith must release that belief before you believe.
But today, we Christians believe without faith product.
Faith must bring that belief before we can say, "I believe, Jesus is Lord!"
If it is not released by faith and you say you believe Jesus is Lord,
you are speaking to yourself.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
To speak of Jesus, faith must release that belief before it becomes a product or machinery.
"I believe, Jesus is Lord" - by what authority?
Yes, the authority is: The belief in my heart is released by faith out of my mouth.
Because belief rests in the heart.
There's no other place for Him.
That's the only place where He lives. He lives in our heart,
and it is released by faith out of our mouth.
Let's start something. Are you ready to start with me?
We will continue to build on it.
Meditation is of heart. Thinking is of mental assent.
Faith is not a mental assent.
Faith is not an intellectual agreement.
To have this faith now, all what you have seen and heard since morning,
and what you are hearing now, begin to meditate on it.
Meditation is of heart, not of mental assent.
The faith bracelet I gave you is not of mouth or of mental assent.
It is of heart and when your heart is engaged in something,
your body, face, appearance, faculty will remain quiet.
No one will know you are saying or doing something.
But today...
It's not of your heart but of your mouth.
Meditation is a visit with God.
If you want to visit Jesus, just meditate in His Word.
You will soon see Him, you will visit Him.
Come on, brother. Come here.
Stand here. I want to demonstrate something.
Stand here.
Come, stand here.
You see this lady is very close to this man.
Take, for example, that this man is Jesus, and she is close to Him.
My brother is a bit far; further than this woman.
If you want to go to Jesus, you will get there before this man.
So if we start meditation now, it will depend on the distance you are to Jesus.
Meditation is a visit with who?
With God.
You want to go and visit Him.
If the sister starts to meditate on God's Word,
and this man also starts to meditate on God's Word,
this woman will get to Jesus before this man.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So therefore, this is just a visit with Him.
You want to go and visit Him. To start the visit, it is not by running.
You cannot run to Jesus, you cannot cry to Jesus.
Crying cannot take you to Jesus.
Dancing cannot take you to Jesus.
Running cannot take you to Jesus. Walking cannot take you to Jesus.
Eloquent speech cannot take you there.
If you memorise the Bible, it cannot take you to Jesus.
The only thing that can take you there is when you begin to meditate on God's Word
and turn it over and over again in your heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Meditation is of man's heart. Man's heart means man's spirit.
Like I have said, Bible faith is of man's heart - man's spirit.
And someone can also be here.
So if this woman calls, "Jesus!", He would likely hear it before this man.
I told you that faith is a Heavenly currency that purchases Heavenly resources.
What are we purchasing?
Salvation, healing, blessing and prosperity.
They are Heavenly resources.
The amount of faith you have is the amount of Heavenly resources.
She seems to have more than this man.
This woman is having more Heavenly currency than this man.
If she just says, "Jesus!", she will likely cash.
This man will say, "Jesus!" 20 times before he cashes what this woman cashes saying, "Jesus!" once.
You may be seated. Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Faith is an object that grows and develops in our heart or man's spirit.
Heart means spirit. As you know, spirit of man means heart.
So what I'm doing here now, by the time I reach there and say, "Jesus!",
the man begins to walk.
That does not mean that you don't have faith.
Maybe you are likely a bit further.
Maybe I'm a bit closer than you.
That's why when I say, "Jesus!", He answers.
You think you cannot do the same. You can do it but you are a bit further.
You just need to begin to meditate on God's Word and turn it over and over again.
You may overtake me.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
No one is born without that seed.
S-E-E-D
It is there, but maybe it is dormant.
It's just like a man saying, "I am poor" because you don't have money in the pocket.
No! A man that is poor is not a man that does not have money in the pocket.
It's a man without vision.
It is when our vision is closed - when it comes to an issue of blessing and
you don't have a vision for that, that's when you are poor.
So in the same way, people say, "I don't have faith".
Who told you that you don't have faith?
It's dormant - you have faith.
Faith activates prayer. Write it down.
You talk of activation. Faith activates prayer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
90% of my teaching is about faith because that is the only thing that pleases God.
You don't need to go to Heaven to see Jesus.
Religious people believe they must go to Heaven to see God.
Jesus came to restore the fellowship and relationship between God and man.
We are coming from a religious angle - all of us -
and we refuse to leave this idea of religionism - the idea of this is how it should be.
Yesterday's idea - we are still carrying it on to Christianity.
There is a difference between religion and Christianity.
That is why we receive so many attacks today.
Anything close to Jesus receives attack.
If you are not close to Jesus, you don't have a problem.
But when you try to be close to Him, you are in trouble - in the hands of satan.
That is why there is so much attack today on Christianity - everywhere.
With that, Christians are not united.
So who is the Christian? Christianity is unity.
Christianity is not disunity.
Christianity is unity. Tell you neighbour.
Christianity is unity.
That is how we know a Christian. You can see them. They unite by love.
They greet by love. Their love sees beyond hatred.
Their love sees beyond attack. When you attack me, the love in me sees beyond that.
So that is it. Their love sees beyond.
But religious love does not see beyond attack.
When you attack them, they attack you back.
It is what you do to them, they do to you.
But in our case, when you do evil to us, we do good to you.
That is the Christianity that Jesus left behind - love your neighbour as yourself.
Your neighbour could be your enemy or those who do not share the same faith with you.
"Love them all" - this is what Jesus said,
This is the teaching of Jesus. What are we doing now?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Love your neighbour as yourself.
Your neighbour could be your enemy or those who do not share the same faith with you.
Love them first.
Don't say, "Because he's not a Christian, I don't want to see him".
You don't want to have anything to do with him.
Love sees beyond.
It is when I love you, you can know who I am and the God I am serving.
I can only win your soul when you are close to me - not at a distance.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Draw me close to You
Never let me go
I lay it all down again
To hear You say that I'm Your friend
You are my desire
Lord Jesus
No one else will do
Nothing else will take Your place
To feel the warmth of Your embrace
Help me find a way
Bring me back to You
You're all I want
You're all I ever needed
Help me know You are near
You're all I want
You are my joy, You are my peace
You're all I ever needed
You're all I want
Help me know You are near
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You will see that you must stop thinking about where you have been
and begin to think about where you are going now.
That's the answer and the way out.
When you look at where you are coming from, there's nothing glorifying God.
Meditate about where you are going
and stop thinking about where you are coming from.
In Jesus Christ's name we pray.
What does it take you to accept Jesus genuinely?
The reason why it is difficult is because we believe in majority.
You have good friends, bad friends,
those who can influence you. Because of them, you cannot say no.
Whatever they tell you is what you will follow.
And you are going to be responsible for what you give your life to.
You will give account on the last day.
See Jesus as the final say and let us give all our heart.
Right now, open your lips and say after me:
Lord Jesus, I'm a sinner.
Come into my heart.
Save my soul.
Lord Jesus, save my soul.
Make me a channel - a channel of shining light where there is darkness.
Make me a channel - a channel of obedience where there is disobedience.
Make me a channel - a channel of pardon where there is injury.
In Jesus Christ's name we pray.
Amen.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Being a channel of shining light, out there in darkness.
We are in the world, we are not part of them.
Because in the world - full of darkness.
But when you are a channel - a channel of shining light - and you're walking in the world,
a channel of shining light walking in the midst of darkness.
There's so much injury and injustice, and now you're a channel of pardon.
So it is time now to give yourself to prayer.
Where you are accused wrongly - temptation, persecution - give yourself to prayer.
Thank You, Lord. You may be seated.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Begin to meditate. That will keep you busy.
There is nothing you have not done or seen.
The only thing you have not done well is your relationship with God.
It is time now.
Begin to meditate.
Lord Jesus, come into my heart. I am a sinner.
Come into my heart; wash me with Your precious blood.
Save my soul.
Lord Jesus, make me a channel of direction where there is no direction,
a channel of way where there is no way,
a channel of pardon where there is injustice.
Begin to refill yourself now.
Lord Jesus, I am a sinner. Come into my heart.
Don't say come into me. He lives in our heart.
Come into my heart.
Wash me with your precious blood.
That precious blood is the blood of Jesus.
And save my soul.
If you are a type that lies; you can lie anywhere -
make me a channel - a channel of truth where there is lying.
Before you know it, where you want to lie, you will resist it
because you have called for help.
You have now become a channel of truth. You cannot lie again.
So you begin to fill yourself - fill yourself.
Make me a channel of truth where there is lying,
a channel of blessing where there is poverty.
Before you know it, you become complete two natures.
Because right now, it is like it is only one nature that is working.
Are you with me?
I said you have two natures but only one is working. The other one is shut down.
Which one is working? Human nature.
Your divine nature is shut down.
It is shut down.
That's why it's difficult for you to meditate. You can't meditate.
You struggle to say it in your heart because you cannot.
You struggle to say it because you are not used to it.
Every human being has two natures but today, people's divine nature is shut down.
It's only the human nature that is working, and human nature cannot pray.
The Bible says we don't know how to say a word in prayer.
We don't know how to pray but the Holy Spirit helps us to pray - that is divine nature.
We cannot meditate with human nature. You can only meditate with divine nature.
Because divine nature is of man's heart.
Divine nature is of man's spirit while human nature is this mental assent.
Memorising things - that is human nature.
That's why you have time to say, "Jesus, kill my enemies,
divide them, kill them, I sent back to sender."
Because there is nothing human nature cannot say.
It's killing, killing, killing; destroy, destroy, destroy.
The human nature wants to retaliate; they derive joy in retaliation
but your divine nature leaves all for God.
Divine nature, today, seems to be dormant, unused.
We need to revive it, we need to clean it.
We need to clean it very well, to revive it for action.
Thank you. God bless you.
I want to pray for your spirit and your heart.
Father, rescue my people.
Rescue my people.
You know you need rescue - you need rescue.
Lord I want to be like Jesus
Inner my heart
That is divine nature.
Lord I want to be like Jesus
Inner my heart
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you. You may be seated. Thank you.